Damilare Oyedeji

Software Developer

SUMMARY

A talented and performance-driven Software Developer, with extensive education and experience in web development. Quick learner, ready for the latest technologies and confident when faced with challenges. I've worked on numerous projects from front-end to back-end (all available to view in my portfolio website). My knowledge and problem solving skills can be a great addition to any engineering team.

SKILLS

PROFICIENT: JavaScript, TypeScript HTML, CSS, ReactJs, ContextAPI, React-Native Redux, TailwindCSS, Styled-Components, Git/GitHub, Bitbucket, Azure

EXPOSURE: NodeJs, ExpressJs, MongoDB.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS: Leadership, Problem Solving, Communication, Teamwork.

CONTACT INFO:

Telephone: +2347031203859 Email: damoye81@gmail.com LinkedIn:

http://linkedin.com/in/damilareoyedeji Github: https://github.com/Fuglydami Portfolio: https://fuglydami.surge.sh/ Lagos, Nigeria.

EMPLOYMENT

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

SBSC Nigeria LTD. | July 2021 - PRESENT

- My role requires building stable and maintainable codebase using React
- Collaborate with the Agile team to ensure products were efficient and technically sound.
- Working directly with client stakeholders to develop technical solutions for business cases.
- Leveraging responsive web frameworks to complete deliverables ahead of schedule.

FRONTEND ENGINEER

Digiscript Tech Solution. | March 2021-July 2021

- My role requires using best practices to build out reusable React components.
- Collaborate with Product Designers, Product Managers ans Software Engineers to deliver compelling user-facing products
- Build and improve clients websites, web apps and many other products for all browsers, devices using React workflow and other tools like styled-components, TailwindCSS and so on

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Netpacks LTD. | Jan 2020 - Feb 2021

- Translated designs and wireframes into high-quality code and wrote application interface code via JavaScript following ReactJs workflow
- Developing features to enhance the user experience
- Collaborating with back-end engineers and designers to improve user experience-

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE

National open university nigeria | 2014-2019

THE COMPLETE WEB DEVELOPER IN 2020 (UDEMY)
Zero to mastery academy | 2020

REACT TUTORIAL AND PROJECT COURSE (UDEMY)
John Smilga React Course | 2020-2021

THE COMPLETE REACT-NATIVE IN 2022 (UDEMY)
Zero to mastery academy | 2022

PROJECTS

CENTRAL ADMIN DASHBOARD (FIRSTBANK NIGERIA)

An admin dashboard built for the subsidiaries of First Bank of Nigeria to provide support for it mobile applications such that the Customer Support Team (First Contact) can carry out some functions like lock/unlock customer profile, view customer's details, device management and so on...

STACK USED: React, Context API, AES.js package to encrypt the request payload, Json web Token for the authentication and Azure.

QUICK RESPONSE CODE RETAIL PAYMENT (FIRSTBANK NIGERIA)

First QR is a simple, secured, convenient and innovative payment mode usable by scanning a QR (Quick Response) Code using a payment app on phones.

It was implemented on the Applications Management Portal that houses all First Bank customer applications

STACK USED: React, Redux, AES.js package to encrypt the request payload, Json web Token for the authentication and Azure.

COMFY SLOTH ECOMMERCE WEBSITE

An e-commerce website that sells a wide range of furnitures.

- Created front-end using React and Context API
- Integrated AuthO to add a login/logout feature which saves your cart data. Google/github sign-in was also added so people that had google or github account could sign-in without registery
- -Integrated stripe to add a checkout feature that allows that customer to purchase items.

Refer to my portfolio for more.